Christian Lawson

Petersburg VA, 23803 <u>cllawson02@gmail.com</u> +1 630 430 5591

Portfolio: https://axzxc99.github.io/Web-Portfolio-Christian-Lawson/

"See a Need, Fill a Need."- Bigweld, Robots (2005). I am a software developer and tech enthusiast with extensive experience in the field. I've been employed ever since I was 17 and my background in coding, problem-solving, and project management allow me to transform ideas into practical solutions. I am motivated by the potential of technology to drive positive change and innovation. Let's connect and work together to shape the future through technology.

Areas of Expertise

- C++
- CSS
- HTML
- Java
- Lua
- SFTP/FTP

- PHP
- JavaScript
- Linux
- Web UX
- HTML5

- XML
- Git
- GitHub
- Node.js
- SSH
- CRON

Work Experience

Service Technician

Arrow International Inc. - Richmond, VA July 2024 to Present

Repairing and replacing slot cabinets for various private social clubs.

Computer Operator Ill

IGT - Richmond, VA August 2022 to July 2024

Troubleshooting & overseeing across major Virginia casino machine operations. We ensure that each casino gaming machine stays within Virginia State Law compliance and hold the venues accountable if need be. We also maintained intra-server connections by facilitating many Linux operations including but not limited to SFTP, FTP, CRON, and SSH

Website Consultant

Independent Contractor for Atelier 11 - Lynchburg, VA July 2020 to August 2022

In addition to full-time work, I found and corrected web problems with Atelier 11, Ltd."s website to support their marketing efforts.

Electrical Assembler

Video Aerial Systems - Madison Heights, VA October 2020 to August 2022

Assembled antennas used for various applications including but not limited to drones, video equipment, and Wi-Fi adapters.

Store Associate

Walmart Inc - Lynchburg, VA October 2018 to December 2019

Unloaded freight truck daily. Stocked freight. Maintained store.

Crew Member

Wendy's Inc - Lynchburg, VA November 2017 to May 2018

Cooked, cleaned, took orders, general maintenance of the restaurant while maintaining honor roll.

Education

Associates

Central Virginia Community College - Lynchburg, VA September 2018 - June 2020 Advanced Diploma E C Glass High School - Lynchburg, VA September 2014 - June 2018

Certifications and Licenses

Virginia Gaming Compliance License

August 2020 to Present

CompTIA ITF+

April 2020 to Present

Introduction to Cloud Computing

January 2022 to Present

Foundational cloud computing course: Key concepts, historical context, industry relevance, top service providers (AWS, Google, IBM, Microsoft), and real-world case studies.

Introduction to Web Development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

March 2022 to Present

Course covers internet servers, cloud app development, front-end and back-end, emphasizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Developing Cloud Native Applications

April 2022 to Present

Develop cloud-native apps: Cloud concepts, dev tools, CNCF, hybrid cloud impact, modernization, Cl/CD. Material Covered:

- Describe Cloud Native and DevOps concepts and methodologies.
- Build and deploy code to IBM Cloud using DevOps tools and services.
- Create a Node.js application on IBM Cloud
- Use REST APIs in your app to store and retrieve data in a "NoSQLCloudantDatabas".

Getting Started with Git and GitHub

May 2022 to Present Git and version control course: Key Git

concepts,

forking, cloning, GitHub teamwork, hands-on labs, public GitHub project.

Developing Cloud Apps with Node.js and React May 2022 to Present Course on server-side JavaScript

frameworks:

and

Node.js, React, cloud app development, favored by developers, caters to IT professionals, recent graduates, and decision-makers.

Assessments

Data Entry - Expert

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to accurately input data and effectively manage databases. Full results: Expert

Basic Computer Skills: PC - Highly Proficient

August 2020

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems. Full results: Highly Proficient

Technical Support - Proficient

August 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network Operations. Full results: <u>Proficient</u>

Programming Fundamentals - Highly Proficient

August 2020

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical competency. Full results: Highly Proficient